okay so I'm here today we have from
好，所以我今天在这里
Eclipse Foundation we have all back here
Eclipse Foundation我们都回到了这里
Wayne beaten and myself and then me it's
韦恩和我自己被殴打，然后是我
Tonya radevich and you may have seen
托尼亚·拉德维奇（Tonya radevich），您可能已经看到
some emails from me lately and the
最近我发了一些电子邮件，
invite for disco
邀请迪斯科
so we'll try from our end to provide
所以我们会尽力提供
update but we also have people from the
更新，但我们也有来自
community helping us out so mmm you
社区帮助我们，让您如此
probably saw Ivar who is even are you
可能看到伊娃（Ivar）甚至是你
here as well on the call yeah okay
在通话中也是，是的，好的
perfect so you all will be helping out
完美，所以大家都会帮忙
with some plans with regards to Jakarta
关于雅加达的一些计划
ie9 and then we'll provide marketing
ie9然后我们将提供市场营销
update you know I'm not sure if you can
更新您知道我不确定是否可以
do the marketing update or if not we'll
进行市场营销更新，否则，我们将
just give the update from the notes from
只需提供来自笔记的更新
like the Nicola who was not able to
就像尼古拉（Nicola）不能
attend today okay yes sorry no if you
今天参加，是的，对不起，如果你不参加
can just do it from the notes that'd be
可以从便笺中做到这一点
great
大
okay fantastic so without further due
好的，太棒了，因此无需进一步
let's let's let's start please feel free
让我们开始吧，请自由
to kind of be interactive and interrupt
有点互动和打扰
us with questions however we did
我们有问题但是我们做了
allocate time for questions and answers
分配时间提问和回答
at the end as well answer any questions
最后还要回答任何问题
you may have
你可能有
so I'm starting up okay oh sure I'll go
所以我要开始了，好吧，我会去的
into a presentation mode just give me a
进入演示模式，请给我一个
second okay you wanna and I'll walk
其次，你想和我一起走
through the first section here get the
通过第一部分，在这里
so we're getting closer to Jakarta eat
所以我们越来越接近雅加达吃
eat at a club setting last time we were
上次我们在俱乐部用餐
together we we had to recognizing that
我们在一起必须认识到
Eclipse last fish 5.1 has been delivered
Eclipse最后一条鱼5.1已交付
and that was gotta eat eight survive as
那得吃八口生存
we're driving out towards Jakarta each
我们每个人都向雅加达开车
ate with them in community there's a lot
在社区里和他们一起吃饭
of work and it's a lot of important work
工作，这是很多重要的工作
that's being done within the community
这是在社区内完成的
to fully move Java EE into into Jakarta
将Java EE完全移入Jakarta
t so exciting times and in parallel as
如此激动人心的时刻
well we're looking at and tough as a
好吧，我们正在寻找和艰难的
community of nothing up on our planning
我们计划中的无人社区
efforts 49 and P bar will get its more
努力49和P bar将得到更多
detail on in the presentation okay cool
在演示文稿中详细介绍，好酷
alright so next next slide Jenna
好吧，所以下一张幻灯片Jenna
alright the pillars of what we call
好吧，我们所谓的支柱
these the pillars of work and it they're
这些工作的支柱，它们是
really AM initiatives that are being
真正的增材制造计划
driven out within the community in order
驱逐出社区
to get us to the full delivery of be8
使我们能够完全交付be8
and the transfer of data you eat into a
并将您吃的数据传输到
sound foundation you know Foundation is
您知道的良好基础
actively working with Oracle on some
在某些方面与Oracle积极合作
some of the supporting agreements left
剩下的一些支持协议
that work continues within the community
在社区内继续工作
we've worked on these facts that's
我们致力于这些事实
bringing the the Java EE M specs into
将Java EE M规范引入
into Jakarta to become Jakarta eats
进入雅加达成为雅加达吃
facts and that what's guiding that is
事实和指导的是
the Jakarta
雅加达
spec process that is currently being
目前正在规范流程
worked on within the spec community and
在规范社区内工作，
lean beam give us a little update on
倾斜梁给我们一些更新
that in his action so the very important
在他的行动中，非常重要
work with regards to having
工作有关
specifications for a 90 lock in
90锁的规格
perspective as well as a basis for for
观点以及
future innovation in inter peridot you
橄榄石未来的创新
know what's always been fundamental to
知道什么一直是
do what the Java has been tcks
做Java曾经做过的事情
and testified ability gets and with the
并经过验证的能力与
TCK for Jakarta not list that was I'm
雅加达的TCK没有列出我的名字
sorry there are some background noise if
对不起，如果有一些背景噪音
you can go on mute that would be
你可以继续静音
fantastic
太棒了
maybe the audio is good yeah I can hear
也许声音很好，是的，我能听到
you guys okay where's their question not
你们好，他们的问题不在哪里
for myself okay cool so with TCGA front
对自己来说还不错，所以在TCGA前端
the PC K of course is what is
PC K当然是什么
contributed and is as host to that
做出了贡献，并作为主持人
Eclipse work is underway on the process
Eclipse工作正在进行中
side of it so that Jakarta has has a TCK
它的侧面，以便雅加达有一个TCK
process that will explain how the TCK is
解释TCK如何的过程
run and and how certification is is
运行以及认证的方式
achieved so that that that pillar is
取得成就，使那个支柱
being actively worked on and in
正在积极地工作
conjunction with that and the spec one
与那个和规范一结合
is really formalizing the approach for
确实是正式的方法
declaring a spec final where you find it
声明规格最终版本
has it labeled tcks and so on it's it's
有标签的tcks，等等，是
important set of details that we need
我们需要的重要细节
clarity on so we've served it up as a
明确，因此我们将其作为
pillar to make sure that it gets all the
支柱，以确保获得所有
attention that's needed in order to make
需要注意的是
sure that those that want to head down
确保那些想要低头的人
the path of certification really you
认证的路径真的是您
know known to understand clearly how to
知道，知道清楚地知道如何
get it done now in the compatible
现在在兼容机上完成它
implementation front that's uh that's
实施前，那是
really running the TCK which maps on to
真正运行映射到的TCK
the specifications that that work is is
工作的规格是
actually getting underway
真正开始
because the the TCK is at is that
因为TCK在
eclipse and you know as we drive towards
日食，当我们驶向
Jakarta ee8 certification and we do
雅加达EE8认证，我们做到了
expect to see eclipses GlassFish open
希望看到月食GlassFish开放
Liberty Pierre server wildfly and Tommy
Liberty Pierre服务器Wildfly和Tommy
you know achieve achieved certification
你知道取得了认证
at you know at some point once the once
在某个时候一次
the the specs have declared are declared
声明的规格已声明
final so that'll be exciting and
最后，这将令人兴奋，
conjunction with that of course is our
与那当然是我们的结合
the marketing act expects and we're
市场营销法期待着我们
marketing we're looking to the the
营销我们正在寻找
marketing committee to really formalize
营销委员会真正正式化
the local usage guidelines so that we've
当地的使用准则，以便我们
got clarity on how sailing ship logo and
清楚了解帆船徽标和
so on as well as PR activities that will
以及公关活动
support Jakarta ee8 so in a coordinated
支持雅加达ee8
way within the community these efforts
这些努力在社区内
these initiatives are are moving along
这些举措正在推进
and and of course as I mentioned earlier
当然，正如我前面提到的
moving along and parallel with Jakarta
与雅加达平行移动
89 really split phases to get clarity on
89个真正的分阶段进行澄清
what where it's going next
接下来会发生什么
alright so how can you help
好吧，你怎么能帮忙
and this really is an initiative that's
这确实是一项举措
owned and driven within within the
在内部拥有和驱动
Jakarta community so it is essential
雅加达社区，因此必不可少
that that that you do help and you do
你所做的帮助和你所做的
get involved part of what's important
参与重要的部分
are the agreements that that underpin
是支撑的协议
what we do the membership contribute
我们为会员所做的贡献
committee agreement the work group just
委员会同意工作组
a patient agreement
病人协议
these agreements need to get to get
这些协议需要得到
executed so that we've got the right
执行，以便我们有权利
underlying governance to to the project
项目的基础治理
so if you do have questions you know
因此，如果您有任何疑问，就知道
reach out to the foundation we can we
伸出我们的基础
can help with the with the agreement
可以帮助达成协议
understanding and what where you're at
了解和你在哪里
and what needs to what needs to get done
什么需要完成
and it was part of the the spec process
这是规范流程的一部分
that that Wayne will getting into next
韦恩将进入下一个
we will be doing a restructuring reviews
我们将进行重组审查
for its specifications the pmc will be
对于其规格，PMC将
fully engaged and owning and driving and
充分参与并拥有和驾驶
helping get that work done
帮助完成工作
within within the vac projects that will
在vac项目中
be created out of the existing projects
从现有项目中创建
again in more details to the follow you
再次以更多详细信息关注您
know part of that will be renaming to
知道其中的一部分将重命名为
Jakarta names and all that will will get
雅加达的名称以及所有这些都将得到
will get work and be part of the process
将得到工作并成为流程的一部分
that will be fully implementing in order
将会全面实施
to get the Jakarta ee8 spec documents
获得Jakarta ee8规格文件
done next slide I and you know what what
在下一张幻灯片中完成了，你知道什么
project wouldn't be complete without a
没有一个项目就不会完成
Kanban board so there is here is a
看板板所以这里有一个
project board in github that's been been
github中的项目委员会
assembled by by the community to
由社区聚集到
organize the work as well as in the
组织工作以及
left/right fashion you know I spell out
你知道我拼写的左/右时尚
what what needs to get done in order for
为了做什么需要做什么
us to evolve the existing projects into
我们将现有项目发展为
into spec projects Wow next one and you
进入规格项目哇，下一个，你
know staying connected in always always
知道永远保持联系
important so I do make time for these
重要的是，我会为此花些时间
community engagement opportunities you
您的社区参与机会
know we'd love your input on what's
知道我们很乐意您的意见
working tribution x' on to these two
对这两个的贡献x'
these sessions and these opportunities
这些会议和机会
to to blog and and spread the good word
去博客和传播好词
of what we're doing within jacquard EEE
提花EEE中我们所做的事情
so get involved be engaged and of course
所以参与进来当然
the mailing lists are a great place to
邮件列表是
ask questions and find out more as if I
提出问题并了解更多
may just join that I also want to point
可能只是加入，我也想指出
out too that if you wanna sign up for a
如果您想注册一个
talk or suggested talk
谈话或建议谈话
we created a spreadsheet to spreadsheet
我们创建了一个电子表格到电子表格
so we can hear from you and become more
这样我们就可以收到您的来信并获得更多
interactive and yeah
互动的，是的
please blog and particularly want to
请写博客，特别想
draw your attention on blogging with
吸引您的关注
regards to your involvement with Jakarta
关于您参与雅加达
he is going to be become more engaged so
他将变得更加订婚
we would love to hear about your
我们很想听听您的信息
enrollment Thank You Tanya all right
报名谢谢Tanya好的
over to over the lane beaten into the
从头到尾
you can drive know if you could just
你可以开车知道你是否可以
continue driving that would be great so
继续驾驶那太好了，所以
I actually do hear some typing could
我确实听到一些打字可能
everyone if you're not preparing to to
每个人，如果您不准备
to ask a question or join in the
问一个问题或加入
conversation can you just please mute
对话，你能打个招呼吗
thank you oh that sounds way better okay
谢谢哦，听起来更好
carry on please alright next slide good
请继续进行下一张幻灯片好
so in the last month I guess we pushed
所以在上个月，我想我们推动了
out a new version of the Eclipse
推出新版本的Eclipse
Foundation specification process like
基础规范流程如
any new new new process that we create
我们创建的任何新的新流程
you know we tend to rapidly evolve it as
你知道我们倾向于迅速发展
we discover deficiencies so we we notice
我们发现不足之处，因此我们注意到
a couple of things that needed to be
需要做的几件事
addressed and we worked on that the
解决，我们致力于
Eclipse Foundation specification process
Eclipse Foundation规范过程
is not strictly owned by the well not
不是由井严格地拥有
even at all not at all owned by the
即使根本不属于
Jakarta ee working group or the
雅加达EE工作组或
specification committee of that working
该工作的规范委员会
group but they have been instrumental in
小组，但是他们在
assembling it and very you know their
组装它，非常你知道他们的
their input into this process has been
他们对该过程的投入是
very valuable as we move forward and
在我们前进的过程中非常宝贵，
roll out the specification and process
推出规格和过程
to other groups will engage with a a
其他团体将与
wider community to to evolve it further
更广泛的社区以进一步发展
but but again to this point the jacquard
但是提花提花
EEE specification committee has been
EEE规范委员会已经
been fantastic in there
那里很棒
and their help with this we made a few
和他们的帮助，我们做了一些
minor language clarifications I say
我说的次要语言说明
minor but because I knew what I meant
小，但因为我知道我的意思
when when I typed the words so we made
当我输入单词时
some some lang at is some language to
一些语言是某种语言
make it so that other people would would
做到让其他人会
better know what I meant and and we
更好地了解我的意思，我们
spent some energy to really call out all
花了一些精力真正召集所有
the different sorts of releases and the
不同类型的发行和
the sorts of engagement that are
那种参与
required for each of the types of
每种类型都需要
releases now major and minor release if
现在发布主要版本和次要版本，如果
you look at the document you'll notice
你看一下你会注意到的文件
that we group those together really
我们真的把那些组合在一起
those have meaning more to the
那些对更多意义
individual they're really no different
个人，他们真的没什么不同
as far as the process is concerned
就过程而言
generally we take the a similar notion
通常我们采用类似的概念
or at least in my mind we take a similar
或者至少在我看来，我们采取类似
notion to how semantic versioning work
语义版本控制的工作原理
so major releases may involve API
因此主要版本可能涉及API
breakage and minor releases editions the
破损和次要发行版
service release is errata or fixes that
服务版本是勘误表或已修复
sort of thing
那类的东西
anyway from a process point of view
无论如何从过程的角度
service releases are different from
服务版本与
major and minor releases we also
主要和次要版本，我们也
formalize is more what the specification
规范化更规范
committees ballot process looks like in
委员会的投票过程看起来像
the previous version we basically stated
我们基本上说的先前版本
that approval was required and in this
该批准是必需的，并且在此
version we qualified what what the
版本我们限定什么
approval process actually looks like in
批准过程实际上看起来像
terms of a duration of of how long about
持续多长时间的条件
it that takes place and and and and
它发生和
whatnot there is a of course a Kanban
当然没有看板
board a project board in github that
在github上登上一个项目委员会
it's now now closed but if you're
现在已经关闭，但如果您
interested in seeing specific details
有兴趣查看具体细节
and discussion related to the changes
和有关变化的讨论
there's a URL at the bottom of this
在此底部有一个URL
slide next slide please thank you I
幻灯片下一张幻灯片，谢谢我
thought I would just take a run at
以为我会跑到
describing the relationship between some
描述一些之间的关系
of these process documents and kind of
这些过程文档以及
an interesting twist Tonya and I both
一个有趣的转折托尼亚和我俩
had the same problem with this document
这个文件也有同样的问题
and ultimately I decided to go with this
最终我决定去
I've actually attempted to draw it in a
我实际上试图将其绘制在
UML sort of fashion and that we both
UML是一种时尚，我们俩
observed that I did it upside down but
观察到我倒挂了
anyway the the development process is
无论如何，开发过程是
kind of the the route or they you know
那种路线，或者他们知道
the super super document that guides the
指导
the manner by which development is done
完成开发的方式
at the Eclipse Foundation that defines
在Eclipse Foundation中定义
our open-source rules of engagement
我们的开源参与规则
openness transparency vendor neutrality
公开透明供应商中立
meritocracy driven responsibilities that
精英管理的责任
sort of thing it defines what a
它定义了什么
committer is what a project is project
提交者就是项目
leads committers sorry centimeters twice
导致提交者对不起厘米两次
PMC's because committers are super
PMC是因为提交者超级
important our whole release process and
重要的是我们整个发布过程
how we do reviews that's all described
我们如何进行评论
by the Eclipse development process the
通过Eclipse开发过程
Eclipse Foundation specification process
Eclipse Foundation规范过程
builds on that to provide some guidance
在此基础上提供一些指导
regarding how specification projects
关于如何规范项目
work their lifecycle how the
工作他们的生命周期
specification committee interacts with
规格委员会与
the process specifically in terms of how
该过程特别是关于如何
they do their approval process through a
他们通过
balloting process but fundamentally the
投票过程，但从根本上讲
the eclipse foundation specification
蚀基础规范
process is set up to manage the
建立流程来管理
intellectual property flows that that
知识产权流向
could occur around specifications right
可能会在规格正确的地方发生
so most of basically well basically
所以大部分基本上都很好
everything that's in that document is
该文档中的所有内容是
about ensuring intellectual property
关于确保知识产权
flow is managed properly now that is
现在可以正确管理流量
kind of generally how specification work
一般而言，规范的工作方式
is done at the Eclipse Foundation it is
是在Eclipse Foundation上完成的
possible and in fact the is it's
可能，实际上是
actually possible for for top-level
对于顶级人才实际上是可能的
projects to customize how the Eclipse
项目如何定制Eclipse
development process is engaged in we
我们从事开发过程
when we set this up we knew that
当我们进行设置时，我们知道
different working groups we're going to
我们要去的不同的工作组
have different requirements
有不同的要求
slightly different requirements so the
要求略有不同，因此
the Eclipse Foundation specification
Eclipse Foundation规范
process provides the baseline and this
过程提供了基线，
is what must be done to do specification
是做规格必须要做的
work at a minimum and then it permits
至少工作，然后允许
for different working group Jakarta EEE
雅加达EEE的不同工作组
working group to tune or customize or
工作组进行调整或自定义，或
specialize the the process so in
这样专门化过程
this case the jacquard EEE specification
这种情况下提花EEE规范
process we've been working with the
我们一直在与
specification committee and most of the
规格委员会和大多数
customizations are around the time
自定义是在时间
timing of when we do reviews when we run
我们运行时进行评论的时间
specification committee ballots how long
规格委员会投票多长时间
those ballots will run for so it's kind
这些选票会参加，所以很
of just sort of tuning kind of
只是一种调整
increasing a couple of time periods to
增加了两个时间段
make sure that the various stakeholders
确保各个利益相关者
have sufficient and time to review
有足够的时间审查
content before proving a review for
内容，然后证明对
example next slide please
请举例下一张幻灯片
in terms of where we are in the process
根据我们在过程中的位置
of engaging in real specification work
从事实际规格工作
at the Eclipse Foundation with the
在Eclipse基金会
jacquard EEE we we have a bunch of
提花EEE，我们有一堆
projects that have API code and right
具有API代码且正确的项目
now all of the projects that are engaged
现在所有参与的项目
in that sort of work are just regular
在那种工作中只是正常的
old Eclipse projects open source
旧的Eclipse项目开源
projects that are basically subject to
基本上受制于的项目
the Eclipse development process what we
Eclipse开发过程中我们
need to do is convert those into
需要做的就是将它们转换成
specification projects so that they can
规范项目，以便他们可以
engage in real specification work to do
从事实际的规范工作
that we need to have this jacquard EEE
我们需要有提花EEE
specification process nailed down and
详细说明规范过程，
I'm hopeful that we will we're getting
我希望我们会得到
close to that we need to have the
接近我们需要
various committers engaged in the
从事
project projects to have be covered by
项目范围
the necessary paperwork which I think we
我认为我们必要的文书工作
talked about elsewhere and we need to
在其他地方谈论过，我们需要
have scope statements for the various
有各种范围的声明
specifications now many the scope
规格现在很多范围
defines the boundaries under which the
定义边界
or by which the the project team will
或项目团队将通过该方式
operate kind of the the range of
操作范围的种类
functionality that the the project that
该项目的功能
specification project will define for
规范项目将为
example this is a this was considered a
例如，这是一个被认为是
strong requirement as part of managing
强烈要求，作为管理的一部分
the intellectual property flows so we
知识产权流动，所以我们
need this before we can move forward and
在我们继续前进之前需要这个
that was the Kanban board that Paul
那是保罗的看板板
presented earlier and we're inviting
之前介绍过，我们正在邀请
everybody project team's project leads
每个人项目团队的项目负责人
in particular to engage in that process
特别是参与这个过程
we're gonna start doing that just for
我们将开始只是为了
example and also a piece of this and
例子，还有一部分
that we believe we have this piece
我们相信我们有这块
sorted is we're gonna actually rename
排序是我们实际上要重命名
some of these projects so I've got an
其中一些项目，所以我有一个
example here what we currently call the
这里的例子我们目前称为
Eclipse project for servlet which was
用于servlet的Eclipse项目
always intended as a placeholder name
始终用作占位符名称
we're going to move forward with a
我们将继续前进
project named Jakarta servlet give just
名为Jakarta servlet的项目
an example of one of the projects next
接下来的一个项目的例子
slide this next slide is really just the
这张幻灯片实际上只是
summary of some of the things that have
总结一些东西
already been stated project scope those
已经说明过的项目范围
project scopes will also have a
项目范围也将有一个
specification scope there's a question
规格范围有一个问题
yeah Wayne this is just McConnell about
是的，韦恩，这只是麦康奈尔
the the the previous slide yep
是上一张幻灯片
what's being done with the existing
现有的是做什么的
projects that have already released
已经发布的项目
artifacts and stuff into maven central
文物和东西进入Maven Central
outside of all these process process
在所有这些流程之外
specifications and all that kind of
规格和所有此类
stuff is there no more of that until
东西再也没有了
these things are locked in or is it just
这些东西被锁住了还是仅仅是
sort of the Wild West oh alright well it
有点狂野的西部哦，好吧
shouldn't be a Wild West because there's
不应该是狂野的西部，因为
a lot of artifacts that have been
大量的人工制品
released into maven central and you know
发布到Maven Central，你知道
like the servlet one that sort of
像servlet这样的
happened out of nowhere okay so maybe we
发生在哪里，好吧，也许我们
can talk details
可以谈细节
offline Jesse and maybe report back to
离线Jesse并可能向报告
the group but so right now the intention
该小组，但现在打算
is to take the existing projects and
是承担现有项目，
convert them into specification projects
将它们转换为规范项目
and then kind of and then implement the
然后再执行
proper specification process as part of
适当的规范过程是
the release of GlassFish 5.1 we did
我们完成了GlassFish 5.1的发布
engage in a process of taking the
参与
content that has been contributed to
已贡献的内容
date and pushing that out to maven
日期并将其推送到行家
central in a kind of like as in the
中央像
Jakarta group but there again if I'm
雅加达小组，但如果我再次出现
curious and again I'm not sure I want to
又好奇又不确定我想
explore that right now I'm curious to to
现在探索，我很好奇
understand and how you mean wild west
了解以及您如何理解狂野西部
and if you do I will contact you after
如果您愿意，我会在之后与您联系
the call well I I talked to you about
我跟你说过的电话
that all right I sent your mail on that
好吧，我就这样发送了您的邮件
quite some time ago I'm just wondering
相当一段时间以前，我只是想知道
whether or not we were going to we
我们是否要去我们
expect to see any more of that kind of
希望看到更多这样的
behavior or is is the the
行为还是
process in place now that those kinds of
流程已经到位，
things are not gonna happen anymore so
事情不会再发生了，所以
the like the GlassFish thing you're
就像您是GlassFish一样
referring to I guess sure now their
指的是我现在确定
project teams are currently governed by
项目团队目前由
the Eclipse development process so if
Eclipse开发过程中，如果
they are making releases they are
他们正在发布
subject to that so a release needs to be
受此限制，因此需要发布
covered by a review of some form if
如果某种形式的评论涵盖
they're doing service releases that's
他们正在做服务发布
just part of the process
只是过程的一部分
i reaiiy as I recall one of the
我回忆起其中之一
challenges was as we were doing this
挑战在于我们正在这样做
bootstrapping process
引导过程
the responsibilities within the projects
项目内的职责
were not entirely clear or enforced and
并不完全清楚或强制执行，并且
we need to tighten that up as we thank
我们要收紧它，谢谢
you for your question sorry if I punted
您的问题对不起，如果我插话
too much the for the Scopes projects
对于Scopes项目来说太多了
have a scope so the project scope will
有范围，所以项目范围将
be you know for example to implement the
您是否知道例如实施
spera to to write the specification
spera编写规范
document employ or provide an API and
文件使用或提供API，以及
and possibly a TCK so interpret
还有可能是TCK，所以解释
individual projects may implement some
个别项目可能会实施一些
subset of those things or you know and
这些东西的子集，或者您知道并且
that can be a future looking statement
可以成为未来的声明
as well even if the certain TCK is not
即使某些TCK不是
currently part of a project it could be
目前是项目的一部分
you know at some point in the future
你知道将来的某个时候
it's in scope the specifications
在规格范围内
themselves also need a description so
自己也需要描述，所以
you know I can say I can picking on
你知道我可以说我可以接
servlet you know I can say that the
servlet，您知道我可以说
servlet Jakarta servlet project
servlet Jakarta servlet项目
implements the document that the IEEE
实施IEEE的文件
API in the TCK and then a description of
TCK中的API，然后描述
what the servlet specification is and I
servlet规范是什么，我
should add I went through an exercise of
应该加上我经历了
trying to actually sort that out and it
试图真正解决它，它
turns out it was more difficult than I
原来这比我难
had hoped but not impossible anyway and
曾经希望但并非不可能，并且
that's something we need to work with
这是我们需要合作的东西
the the pmc and the specification
pmc和规范
committee are going to have to actively
委员会将不得不积极
participate in in that process and then
参与该过程，然后
I listed some paperwork here but again I
我在这里列出了一些文书工作，但我再次
believe that's been discussed
相信已经讨论过了
earlier so with that I'm actually done
之前我已经完成了
with what I wanted to present about
我想介绍的东西
specifications is there any other
规格还有其他
questions I'm happy to answer okay thank
我很乐意回答的问题，谢谢
you
您
I will mute us so oh I know the agenda
我会让我们静音，哦，我知道议程了
says create on the version number yet so
说在版本号上创建，所以
only next what I prayed there on get
只有接下来我祈祷在那里
also to get a page after it's it's also
也要在它之后获得页面
that we started a little bit for just
我们开始只是为了
defining a hypnotist for how to get
定义如何获得催眠师
started with a the roadmap for the next
从下一个路线图开始
releases and that is done on in the
发布，并在
Jakara e-platform
Jakara电子平台
project on the eclipse Unova when we
当我们在日食Unova上进行投影时
have these project boards but also
有这些项目委员会，但也
started here is to gather issues for how
从这里开始是为了收集有关如何
do you want this patent so here we asked
您想要这项专利吗，所以我们在这里问
the community to just contribute
社区贡献力量
everyone can create a issue there so
每个人都可以在那里创建一个问题
just get it in there and then we can
只要把它拿到那里，然后我们就可以
prioritize and discuss it and see how we
确定优先次序并进行讨论，看看我们如何
go with it you also earlier had a before
和它一起去，你也早先有过
Coleman last year the technology
科尔曼去年的技术
community both voices where a lot of
社区的声音在很多地方
people have contributed to what they see
人们为他们所看到的做出了贡献
is important for the future versions of
对于将来的版本很重要
the top
顶端
so of course we will look at this and
所以我们当然会看这个
take these things into the get
把这些东西带进去
observatory turns out some tracking your
天文台原来有些跟踪你
ovation so we have don't lose anything
鼓掌，所以我们没有任何损失
there are also people in the community
社区里也有人
writing blogs about this and we're
写关于这个的博客，我们
trying to keep track like artists law
试图像艺术家法律一样保持轨道
here from Cuellar with where he lists
来自Cuellar的清单
all the specifications he he he's
他的所有规格
involved and and and how a ste they all
参与，以及如何他们都
this work is it's ongoing its kind of
这项工作正在进行中
with gathering all these sources of
收集所有这些来源
information and trying to get it into
信息并试图将其纳入
this jacquard a platform project and get
这个提花平台项目，并得到
up so we can get all ashes in there and
这样我们就可以把所有的灰烬都放在那里
then we can can distribute them to the
然后我们可以将它们分发到
different projects to stick update on
坚持更新的不同项目
all this I encourage you to join the
所有这一切，我鼓励您加入
platform mailing list so that's the
平台邮件列表，因此
jacory platen Deb
雅克里·潘德
also look at the product home for the
也可以在产品主页上查看
mapping project and of course also
制图项目，当然还有
follow the the project on get out
跟随项目前进
so that's more or less where we are at
所以差不多就是我们所处的位置
the planning of the car I be next or not
汽车计划是我的下一个还是不下
in order whatever version is gonna be so
以便无论版本如何
that was what I have planned to say any
那就是我计划说的
questions so let me jump into the
问题，让我跳进
marketing update if that's okay I will
行销更新，如果可以的话，我会
share email from like the Nicola and and
分享来自Nicola和
then go through that just give me a
然后通过那只是给我一个
second here and I will put it all the
第二个，我会把所有的
material
材料
available to you guys up to the couple
你们对这对夫妇可用
so are just a little bit on the
所以只是一点点
marketing committees we don't have the
我们没有的营销委员会
chair at this point and and you know the
在这一点上，你知道
committee is managing that through
委员会正在通过
rotating into the role on a monthly
轮流担任角色
basis we are meeting twice a month and
我们每个月开会两次
that is actually relatively new starting
这实际上是一个相对较新的开始
in February we started with us
从二月份开始
cadence previously we were meeting on
节奏我们之前在开会
the weekly basis so where we're at as
每周的基础，所以我们现在
right now we're we're looking into the
现在我们正在调查
approving Jakarta members and
批准雅加达成员并
compatibility logos and determining the
兼容性徽标并确定
guy we're trying to determine also the
我们正在尝试确定的家伙
how to use those and and and created
如何使用那些和和并创建
active documents as well the logos
活动文档以及徽标
however we we will be voting on them
但是我们将对它们进行投票
finally actually that's tomorrow March
终于是明天三月
28th so we will share that with the
28日，我们将与
community I do believe the community at
我确实相信社区
least it be a larger or everyone who is
至少是更大的人
signed up on the working group
签约工作组
distribution mailing list was consulted
已查询分发邮件列表
on on these as well we are planning a
在这些方面，我们也在计划
couple of different events around the
围绕着几个不同的事件
Jakarta EE one of them was Jakarta
Jakarta EE其中之一就是Jakarta
summit and we are still working towards
峰会，我们仍在努力
that but tying it very closely to the
但要与之紧密联系
Jakarta e88 release so depending on the
Jakarta e88发布，因此取决于
plan
计划
for Jakarta Layton and specific dates
雅加达莱顿和特定日期
for release date we're going to pick up
发布日期，我们要去取
and talk about Jakarta summit we're also
谈论雅加达峰会，我们也是
going to oh yeah so there is a work
去哦，是的，所以有一份工作
being done with regards on reviewing the
关于审查
Jakarta 2019 budget well we had the boat
雅加达2019预算很好，我们有船
actually yesterday within the steering
其实昨天在转向
committee and that was approved so we're
委员会，这是被批准的，所以我们
going to acknowledge that on the
要承认的是
upcoming marketing meeting tomorrow we
明天我们即将举行的营销会议
have done tons of updates on the Jakarta
在雅加达做了很多更新
II website and if you go and look at
II网站，如果您去看看
there you will see the blogs you will
在那里，您将看到博客
see the resources page and of course you
请参阅资源页面，当然您也可以
are going to see Jakarta a developer
将要见雅加达开发人员
survey that we just closed yesterday and
我们昨天刚刚关闭的调查
I'm really hopeful that all of you had a
我真的很希望你们所有人都有
chance to participate and let us know
有机会参与并告诉我们
you know how or the organization are
你知道组织如何
planning to to participate and use
计划参与和使用
Jakarta a going forward we had over 1700
雅加达前进，我们已经超过1700
responses and yeah I that's my name
回应，是的，我就是我的名字
right there I will give the information
就在那里，我将提供信息
about survey results but I didn't intend
关于调查结果，但我没有打算
to look at it yet so I will definitely
看看它，所以我一定会
provide that information as soon as I
我尽快提供该信息
have it so that is what we have from the
拥有它，这就是我们从
marketing summary but you know I would
营销摘要，但您知道我会
love to open
爱开
at this point for your comments
在此发表您的评论
questions concerns because we certainly
问问题，因为我们当然
believe they're there quite a few also I
相信他们也有很多
do want to remind that we don't need
确实要提醒我们，我们不需要
just this meeting just long now go ahead
就在这次会议不久前
[Music]
[音乐]
yeah
是的
so the did you say that the proposed
所以你说建议
budget what's the proof yesterday yes so
预算昨天有什么证明是的
we had reviewed this morn okay let me
我们已经审查了这个早晨好吧，让我
just try to let me try to mute everyone
试着让我尝试让所有人静音
and then please mute all so I will mute
然后将所有静音，让我静音
everyone and then I'll mute yourselves
每个人，然后我会让自己静音
for for the questions can you hear me
对于问题，你能听到我吗
now
现在
oh I know can you hear me I cannot hear
哦，我知道你能听到我吗，我听不到
you Tanya so so I just wanted to
您是Tanya，所以我只想
understand so the so the the proposal
如此理解所以建议
for the marketing budget was reviewed
审查了营销预算
yesterday but not approved no no it was
昨天但没有批准，不，不是
approved so he was so so everything's
批准，所以他是如此，一切都
good
好
okay and can we I guess we'll be
好吧，我想我们会
reviewing that tomorrow marketing okay
回顾明天行销还可以
great thanks Oh
非常感谢哦
and more question yes please go ahead
还有更多问题，请继续
no I'm sorry I just I'm hearing some
不，对不起，我只是听到一些
noise and in the blogs okay all right
噪音和博客中都可以
actually I have a question can you tell
其实我有一个问题可以告诉你
can you go and a little bit into the
你可以去一点点
details of the road map sure I think you
路线图的细节肯定我认为你
know do you want to take this one sure
知道你想确定这一点吗
give me a road map for for the the
给我一个路线图
entire thing that first the the ee8
整个东西，首先是ee8
version and then the nine or or dooming
版本，然后九或或注定
details about the e naught but correctly
关于正确的细节，但正确
correct the the entire yes the general
更正整个是一般
road map for Tony if you can show the
如果可以的话，托尼的路线图
slide yeah I say well I'm just looking
幻灯片，是的，我说很好，我只是在找
for it yes oh I need to share my entire
为此，是的，我需要分享我的全部
screen so just to give me a second
屏幕，只给我一点
and I will be glad to do that okay so
我会很高兴这样做的，所以
going back to or the beginning of the
回到或开始
presentation sorry for looking into
演讲很抱歉
there we go yep too much so this is what
我们太多了，所以这就是
you mean is that yeah is that what you
你的意思是，是的，那是你
mean
意思
yes have a question here could you go a
是的，这里有一个问题，你可以去吗
little bit into details you you have
一点点你拥有的细节
described already but maybe I
已经描述过了，但也许我
is it clear that Jakarta ee8 will be
很明显，雅加达ee8将
exactly have the same technologies like
完全一样的技术
Java e8 so the intention is that we will
Java e8的目的是，我们将
take the existing specifications as they
遵循现有规范
were released for when we did it in
被释放是因为我们在
January when we did the Eclipse class
一月，当我们上Eclipse班
they should fight one release
他们应该打一场
then we also released all the the api's
然后我们还发布了所有的api
and what we will do is actually use the
而我们要做的实际上是使用
same tag of ranch and just update the
相同的牧场标签，只是更新
version numbers do the the renaming and
版本号进行重命名和
actually some some XML namespaces or
实际上是一些XML名称空间或
URLs so we'll keep the changes minimal
网址，因此我们将更改保持在最低水平
as possible so the intention is that it
尽可能的是，目的是
will be more or less exactly the same we
我们或多或少会完全一样
have a doctor for some some small bug
为一些小虫子找医生
fixes if the project teams are able to
修复项目团队是否能够
do that but we will try to limit it so
这样做，但我们会尽力限制它
we will have no no new functionality and
我们将没有任何新功能，并且
no breaking changes okay good thank you
没有重大变化，好的，谢谢
the Eclipse GlassFish for Jakarta heat 9
雅加达热量用Eclipse GlassFish 9
do you have a roadmap for this when this
你有这个的路线图吗
will be released that hasn't been set up
将被释放尚未设置的
yet but I'm pretty sure did I think it's
但是，我很确定我认为这是
Dimitri will be in charge of this as he
Dimitri将负责此工作，因为他
was with the Eclipse flashing final one
与Eclipse闪烁的最后一个
and and he was to head off a similar
而且他要去类似的
project board on github so we can follow
github上的项目委员会，所以我们可以关注
the stages there as soon as he's got
他一到达那里的舞台
around to it but kind of the the thing
围绕它，但有点
that we have to wait for and told we can
我们必须等待，并告诉我们可以
even start that is to get the the
甚至开始就是为了
specification project the process
规范项目流程
defined and also the the trademark
定义以及商标
agreements sign yeah so one one that is
协议签署是的，所以一个是
in work in parallel we can proceed with
在并行工作中，我们可以继续
some of the work and and that's where
一些工作，那就是
the community can get
社区可以得到
engaged providing that the spectral
从事提供频谱
process which we're wrapping up
我们正在总结的过程
hopefully very shortly and the paperwork
希望很短的时间和文书工作
from the commuters is done right then we
通勤者做的正确，然后我们
can start some work in the parallel
可以并行开始一些工作
while we're still working on finalizing
虽然我们仍在努力完成
our trade agreements and working towards
我们的贸易协议，并致力于
getting these specification documents
获取这些规格文件
into our specification projects so
进入我们的规格项目
question thank you very much thank you I
问题非常感谢你，我
see that the similar question is also
看到类似的问题也是
posted on the chat what is the target
在聊天中发布目标是什么
date forward last week 502 Jakari e8 and
上周502 Jakari e8的日期向前
and we cannot get a date yet but as soon
而且我们还不能得到约会，但是很快
as we can the the the 29 January 19th
我们可以的1月29日
but that's already passed obviously so
但这显然已经过去了
yeah this one you have no guesstimate of
是的，这个你没有猜中
that 502 to create so for clarity
为了清晰起见创建的502
January 29th was when Eclipse GlassFish
1月29日是Eclipse GlassFish
5.1 delivered and as you know pointed
5.1已交付，如您所知
out we're not at the point now the
出来，我们现在还不重要
community is not at the point now to
社区现在不是重点
communicate a date for jacquard ee8 or
传达提花ee8的日期或
GlassFish I've got two but there's a lot
GlassFish我有两个，但是有很多
of work going on that's moving us
正在进行的工作使我们感动
towards that towards that objective but
朝那个目标迈进
are we talking years or months no we're
我们是数年还是数月不，我们是
definitely not talking years but at the
绝对不是几年，而是在
same time we cannot we don't want to
同时我们不能我们不想
overstate or over promise and then get
高估或过度承诺，​​然后得到
into trouble okay good thank you
麻烦了好谢谢
without promising anything that we would
没有承诺我们会做的
really really like to have something to
真的很想吃点东西
show when the two big events or the
显示两个重大事件或
major events this fall is going but
今年秋天的重大事件正在发生，但
clicks on Europe and
点击欧洲和
an Oracle one we really really like to
我们真的很喜欢的甲骨文
have something to show that okay but
有一些东西可以表明，但是
it's kind of out of our control
这是我们无法控制的
yeah right Seaver one sorry go ahead
是的，对了Seaver，很抱歉继续
yeah okay thank you very much I've won a
是的，非常感谢，我赢了
question about the yes the connection to
关于是的问题连接到
the Eclipse IDE in the past we had the
过去的Eclipse IDE
GlassFish tools now with Jakarta e8 or
现在使用Jakarta e8或GlassFish工具
let's say also Java he ate the how far
假设Java他吃了多远
or how much have you focused on this and
或您有多少专注于此
what's plans about the Eclipse IDE will
Eclipse IDE的计划是什么
it be like mmm I mean I think that the
就像mmm我的意思是我认为
community expects from you us that we
社区期望您，我们
have something implemented that works
实施一些可行的方法
perfectly since Eclipse best fish it's a
完美，因为Eclipse最好的鱼是
toccata is now and picked up said he's
托卡塔现在被拾起，说他是
on one hand now so what's the plans
一方面，现在有什么计划
there so first and foremost the Eclipse
首先是Eclipse
Foundation is a place where open source
基金会是开源的地方
development works and the Eclipse
开发工作和Eclipse
Foundation does not actually employ any
基金会实际上并没有雇用任何人
of the developers ultimately what the
的开发商最终是什么
Eclipse IDE project decide to do is
Eclipse IDE项目决定要做的是
really up to them and the the amount of
真正取决于他们和数量
energy that comes to the community to
社区的能量
assist them in that sort of activity so
协助他们进行这类活动
this is sort of a non-answer but so we
这有点无法回答，所以我们
we do not include the Eclipse IDE is not
我们不包括Eclipse IDE不
included in any of our current plans
包括在我们目前的任何计划中
around Jakarta EE there is an eclipse
在雅加达（Jakarta）EE附近，日食
GlassFish tools project that has been
GlassFish工具项目已经
created and the GlassFish tools content
创建的GlassFish工具内容
I believe has been transferred to that
我相信已经转移到那个
project and I would invite members of
项目，我会邀请
the community that are interested in
感兴趣的社区
working on that content to to
处理该内容以
investigate that project and contribute
调查该项目并做出贡献
okay I'm interested in true contribute
好吧，我对真正的贡献很感兴趣
to this project but with then I will
参加这个项目，但那时我将
have to
不得不
so through them
所以通过他们
you
您